in part two of this problem
we want our code to output the string
the clouds are blocking the sun
if our local variable sun references the
string
hidden now one way that we could solve
this problem
is to change the condition we provided
to our if statement in part one
compare the value of sun to the string
hidden
[Music]
and change our output string
to the clouds are blocking the sun
this would achieve the desired behavior
and we can see that if we output the
value of sun
run our program a few times
only when the sun is hidden do we output
the string the clouds are blocking the
sun
[Music]
however our problem description
specifies that we should use an unless
statement here
so if we replace if within less now we
have an unless statement
our code is not going to behave as we
would expect
now you can see that when sun is visible
we've output the string the clouds are
blocking the sun
and when the sun is hidden we don't
output anything
so this is the opposite of the behavior
that we want
and that's because when the sun is
hidden
this condition we've provided to our
unless statement evaluates
as true an unless statement will only
execute the body
line 5 when its condition evaluates as
false
so we want to print the string the
clouds are blocking the sun
unless sun is equal to visible
when the value referenced by the local
variable sun
is equal to the string visible we don't
want to output anything
so let's run our code again and now you
can see that
when the sun is visible we don't output
anything
and when the sun is hidden we output the
correct string
[Music]
so unless statements can be very useful
remember that
the code within an unless statement will
only be executed
if its condition evaluates as false